<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Mitosis</string>

    <string name="mitosisDesc"><b>Mitosis</b> is a process where one cell divides itself into two cells. Both of the new cells have the same genetic information as their parent.
        This process can only be done with eukaryotic cells. Some organisms undergo mitosis to reproduce, which is also known as <b>asexual reproduction</b>
        (reproduction with one parent only). Otherwise, mitosis is done by the cells in the body for development and growth. For example, cells in a human baby carry out mitosis
        so the baby can grow into a teenager. In a multicellular organism, cells that undergo mitosis are known as somatic cells. Mitosis goes through 4 stages,
        Prophase, Metaphase, Anaphase, and Telophase (also known as <b>PMAT</b>).</string>
    <string name="interphaseDesc">Interphase is not a phase in mitosis, but is still important to know about because it is the phase that a cell spends most of their life in.
        Additionally, when it becomes time to undergo mitosis, this is the phase where DNA duplicates so both <b>daughter cells</b> (product of cell division) can have an equal
        amount of genetic information as the parent. In this stage, the DNA of the cell (currently called <b>chromatin</b>) is coiled up like spaghetti, and rests within the
        nuclear membrane. When chromatin doubles and condenses, it becomes <b>chromosomes</b>.</string>
    <string name="prophaseDesc">(Three chromosomes are shown for easier understanding) \n \n
        In prophase the chromosomes condense, and the nuclear membrane disappears. On both sides of the cell, little cylinders called <b>centrioles</b> release
        stringlike fibres called <b>spindles</b>.</string>
    <string name="metaphaseDesc">In metaphase, spindles attach to the middle of each centromere. Chromosomes are moved to the middle of the cell (also known as the equator)
        and line up in a single file line.</string>
    <string name="anaphaseDesc">During anaphase, spindle fibres pull sister chromatids apart to opposite sides of cell. The centromere divides with them.</string>
    <string name="telophaseDesc">In the final phase, the nuclear membrane appears on both sides of the cell, surrounding each group of chromosomes.
        The spindles retract, and the cell prepares to be divided. The process where the cell is divided into two daughter cells is known as cytokinesis,
        which happens after telophase. The result are two daughter cells completely identical to the previous cell. Both cells have the same number of chromosomes
        and chromatids as the parent cell, making them <b>diploid cells</b>.</string>

    <string name="meiosisDesc"><b>Meiosis</b> is a process of cell division in which a germ cell creates sex cells <b>(gametes)</b> for <b>sexual reproduction</b>. Meiosis is different
        from mitosis because every daughter cell is unique, and the number of chromosomes in each cell is half the amount of the parent cell. Those are called <b>haploid cells</b>.
        Cells that do meiosis to create sex cells are known as germ cells. They either create a sperm cell or an egg cell, depending on the gender of the organism.
        This sperm or egg later meets another egg or sperm, and mixes into a <b>zygote</b>, which later grows into a child through mitosis. The process of meiosis is a bit
        like mitosis, since they both follow <b>PMAT</b> (prophase, metaphase, anaphase, telophase). However, meiosis goes through PMAT twice to create haploid cells.
        To differentiate between the first division and the second, numbers are added after the name of the process (prophase 1, prophase 2).</string>
    <string name="interphaseDesc2">\n Like mitosis, interphase is not a part of meiosis, but it is still the phase where DNA duplicates so the cell can divide.
        In this stage, the DNA (chromatin) of the cell is coiled up like spaghetti, and rests within the nuclear membrane. When it becomes time undergo meiosis,
        the DNA doubles.</string>
    <string name="prophase1Desc">(Only four chromosomes are shown for easier understanding)\n In prophase 1, the nuclear membrane disappears, and chromosomes condense. Centrioles become active and spindles attach to
        centromeres. However, unlike mitosis, <b>homologous chromosomes</b> move next to each other. Homologous chromosomes are pairs of chromosomes that code for the
        same genetic information. An organism produced from sexual reproduction receives one from their mother, and the other from their father.
        Once they are together, they begin a process between prophase 1 and metaphase 1 known as crossing over.</string>
    <string name="crossingOverDesc">\n Crossing over is when homologous chromosomes exchange genetic information with each other. This is what makes each
        daughter cell at the end of meiosis is unique. When homologous chromosomes exchange DNA, they become <b>recombinant chromosomes</b>.</string>
    <string name="metaphase1Desc">Homologous chromosomes move to the equator (middle) of cell, in pairs. The possibility of getting one recombinant chromosome on the left and
        the other on the right is known as <b>independent assortment</b>.</string>
    <string name="anaphase1Desc">Spindles pull homologous chromosomes apart. There are now sister chromatids on either side of the cell.</string>
    <string name="telophase1Desc">The nuclear membrane may reform, and sister chromatids may uncoil. Spindles retract and cell divides. There are now
        two daughter cells ready to undergo PMAT again. In each cell there are 23 chromosomes, and 46 chromatids.</string>
    <string name="prophase2Desc">The nuclear membrane breaks down. Centrioles become active once again and attach to centromeres connecting the sister chromatid.
        This time, crossing over does not happen.</string>
    <string name="metaphase2Desc">Chromosomes move to the equator of the cell, in a single file line.</string>
    <string name="anaphase2Desc">Sister chromatids are pulled to opposite sides of cell by the spindles. The centromere divides as well.</string>
    <string name="telophase2Desc">The nuclear membrane reappears, spindles retract and each cell divides. If the cells are sperm cells, the end products are four
        unique haploid cells. Otherwise, one egg cell survives and receives all the nutrients while the other three die off. Those are known as polar bodies.
        Gametes have now been created and are ready to interact with another gamete to create a zygote.</string>

    <string name="cytokinesis">Cells after cytokinesis:</string>

    <string name="vocab1"><font color="#660066">Chromosome:</font> condensed DNA \n<font color="#00a3cc">Chromatid:</font> a duplicated copy of a chromosome
        \n<font color="#ff0000">Sister chromatids:</font> two chromatids with the same genetic information \n<font color="#ff3300">Centromere:</font> DNA that links
        two chromatids together. Can also exist with one chromatid. \n<b>Tip</b> - count chromatids by the number of lines connected by the centromere.
        Count chromosomes by the number of centromeres</string>
    <string name="vocab2"><font color = "#00a3cc">Blue:</font> nuclear membrane \n<font color="#ff0000">Red:</font> DNA that is not condensed (chromatin)
        \n<font color="#999999">Grey:</font> nucleoid</string>
    <string name="vocab3"><font color="#00cc00">Green:</font> centrioles \n<font color="#e6e600">Yellow:</font> spindles \n</string>
    <string name="whatPhase">What phase is this?</string>
    <string name="fillBlanks">Fill in the blanks with the word only.</string>

    <string name="disadvantages">Disadvantages</string>
    <string name="advantages">Advantages</string>

    <string name="questionsLeft">Questions left: %1$d</string>
    <string name="score">Score: %1$d</string>
    <string name="correct">Correct! %1$s</string>
    <string name="wrong">Incorrect... %1$s</string>
</resources>